When I came home in 1955 from university at the time of Martin Luther King, a lot of people came home at that time and started having arguments with their parents and grandparents. My father was born in 1885, and he was mildly racially biased. As an Irishman, he hated the English so much he didn't have much emotion for anyone else. (Laughter) But he did have a sense that black people were inferior. And when we said to our parents and grandparents, "How would you feel if tomorrow morning you woke up black?" they said that is the dumbest thing you've ever said. Who have you ever known who woke up in the morning -- (Laughter) -- that turned black? In other words, they were fixed in the concrete mores and attitudes they had inherited. They would not take the hypothetical seriously, and without the hypothetical, it's very difficult to get moral argument off the ground. You have to say, imagine you were in Iran, and imagine that your relatives all suffered from collateral damage even though they had done no wrong. How would you feel about that? And if someone of the older generation says, well, our government takes care of us, and it's up to their government to take care of them, they're just not willing to take the hypothetical seriously. Or take an Islamic father whose daughter has been raped, and he feels he's honor-bound to kill her. Well, he's treating his mores as if they were sticks and stones and rocks that he had inherited, and they're unmovable in any way by logic. They're just inherited mores. Today we would say something like, well, imagine you were knocked unconscious and sodomized. Would you deserve to be killed? And he would say, well that's not in the Koran. That's not one of the principles I've got. Well you, today, universalize your principles. You state them as abstractions and you use logic on them. If you have a principle such as, people shouldn't suffer unless they're guilty of something, then to exclude black people you've got to make exceptions, don't you? You have to say, well, blackness of skin, you couldn't suffer just for that. It must be that blacks are somehow tainted. And then we can bring empirical evidence to bear, can't we, and say, well how can you consider all blacks tainted when St. Augustine was black and Thomas Sowell is black. And you can get moral argument off the ground, then, because you're not treating moral principles as concrete entities. You're treating them as universals, to be rendered consistent by logic. Now how did all of this arise out of I.Q. tests? That's what initially got me going on cognitive history. If you look at the I.Q. test, you find the gains have been greatest in certain areas. The similarities subtest of the Wechsler is about classification,
Cuando volví a mi casa en 1955 de la universidad en el tiempo de Martin Luther King, muchas personas volvieron a sus casas en ese entonces y empezaron a discutir con sus padres y abuelos. Mi padres nació en 1885, y tenía ciertos prejuicios en cuanto a las razas. Como irlandés, odiaba a los ingleses tanto que no tenía sentimientos para otra cosa. (Risas) Pero sí tenía una sensación que las personas negras eran inferiores. Y cuando le dijimos a nuestros padres y abuelos, "¿Cómo te sentirías si en la mañana te despertaras negro?" Ellos dijeron que era la cosa más estúpida que podías haber dicho. ¿A quién conoces que se haya levantado... (Risas) ... y se haya vuelto negro? En otras palabras, estaban obsesionados en lo concreto. Moral y actitudes que habían heredado. No le prestaban atención a lo hipotético, y sin lo hipotético, es muy difícil poder discutir argumentos morales. Tienes que decir, imagínate que estás en Irán, y que tus familiares sufrieron efectos colaterales aunque no hayan hecho nada malo. ¿Cómo te sentirías en esa situación? Y si alguien de una generación más vieja dice: "Bueno, nuestro gobierno nos cuida, y es trabajo de su gobierno el cuidarlos a ellos", no quieren tomar en serio lo hipotético. O imagínate un padre islámico cuya hija ha sido violada, y siente que tiene que matarla por honor. Bueno, está tratando su moral como si fueran palos y piedras que ha heredado, y que son estáticas en la lógica. Es una moral heredada. Hoy diríamos algo como, bueno, imagínate que te dejaran inconsciente y te violaran. ¿Mereces que te maten? Y él diría, bueno eso no está en el Corán. No es uno de los principios que tengo. Pero, hoy se universalizan tus principios. Los presentas como abstracciones y usas la lógica sobre ellos. Si tienes un principio como, las personas no deben sufrir a menos de que sean culpables de algo, y luego excluyes a la gente negra hay que hacer excepciones, ¿no? Hay que decir, bueno, el color de la piel, no se puede sufrir por eso. Debe ser que los negros están de alguna manera manchados. Y no podemos usar evidencia empírica para discutir, ¿o no? Y decir, ¿cómo puedes considerar a todos los negros como impuros cuando San Agustín era negro y Thomas Sowell era negro. Y se pueden eliminar argumentos morales así porque no se están tratando a los principios morales como entidades concretas. Los estás considerando como universales, para ser consistentes por su lógica. ¿Cómo llegamos a esto desde las pruebas de inteligencia? Esto es lo que inicialmente me llevó a la historia cognitiva. Si se mira una prueba de inteligencia, se observa que los aumentos han sido mayores en ciertas áreas. El subexamen de Wechsler es sobre clasificación,
and we have made enormous gains on that classification subtest. There are other parts of the I.Q. test battery that are about using logic on abstractions. Some of you may have taken Raven's Progressive Matrices, and it's all about analogies. And in 1900, people could do simple analogies. That is, if you said to them, cats are like wildcats. What are dogs like? They would say wolves. But by 1960, people could attack Raven's on a much more sophisticated level. If you said, we've got two squares followed by a triangle, what follows two circles? They could say a semicircle. Just as a triangle is half of a square, a semicircle is half of a circle. By 2010, college graduates, if you said two circles followed by a semicircle, two sixteens followed by what, they would say eight, because eight is half of 16. That is, they had moved so far from the concrete world that they could even ignore the appearance of the symbols that were involved in the question. Now, I should say one thing that's very disheartening. We haven't made progress on all fronts. One of the ways in which we would like to deal with the sophistication of the modern world is through politics, and sadly you can have humane moral principles, you can classify, you can use logic on abstractions, and if you're ignorant of history and of other countries, you can't do politics. We've noticed, in a trend among young Americans, that they read less history and less literature and less material about foreign lands, and they're essentially ahistorical. They live in the bubble of the present. They don't know the Korean War from the war in Vietnam. They don't know who was an ally of America in World War II. Think how different America would be if every American knew that this is the fifth time Western armies have gone to Afghanistan to put its house in order, and if they had some idea of exactly what had happened on those four previous occasions. (Laughter) And that is, they had barely left, and there wasn't a trace in the sand. Or imagine how different things would be if most Americans knew that we had been lied into four of our last six wars. You know, the Spanish didn't sink the battleship Maine, the Lusitania was not an innocent vessel but was loaded with munitions, the North Vietnamese did not attack the Seventh Fleet, and, of course, Saddam Hussein hated al Qaeda and had nothing to do with it, and yet the administration convinced 45 percent of the people that they were brothers in arms, when he would hang one from the nearest lamppost. But I don't want to end on a pessimistic note. The 20th century has shown enormous cognitive reserves in ordinary people that we have now realized, and the aristocracy was convinced that the average person couldn't make it, that they could never share their mindset or their cognitive abilities. Lord Curzon once said
y hemos tenido grandes aumentos en ese subexamen de clasificación. Hay otras partes de la prueba de inteligencia que son sobre el uso de lógica en abstracciones. Alguno de Uds. han usado Matrices Progresivas de Raven y se trata sobre analogías. Y en 1900, las personas podían resolver analogías simples. Si les decías: los gatos son como gatos monteses. ¿Cómo son los perros? Ellos responderían: lobos. Pero para 1960, las personas podían atacar a Raven en un nivel mucho más sofisticado. Si les decías: tienes 2 cuadrados seguidos por un triángulo: ¿Qué le sigue a 2 círculos? Ellos dirían: un semicírculo. Porque un triángulo es la mitad de un cuadrado, y un semicírculo, la mitad de un círculo. Para 2012, los estudiantes universitarios, si les decías 2 círculos seguidos por un semicírculo, dos 16 seguidos ¿por qué?, responderían 8, porque 8 es la mitad de 16. Quiere decir que se han apartado tanto del mundo concreto que hasta pueden ignorar la apariencia de los símbolos que se encuentran en la pregunta. Ahora, tengo que decir algo muy desconcertante. No hemos logrado progresar en todos los frentes. Una de las maneras en la que nos gustaría ocuparnos de la sofisticación del mundo moderno es con la política, y a pesar de que se pueden tener principios morales humanos, se puede clasificar, usar lógica, abstracciones; si se es ignorante sobre la historia y sobre otros países, no se puede hacer política. Hemos observado, en una tendencia entre los jóvenes estadounidenses, que leen menos historia y menos literatura y menos material sobre países extranjeros, y son esencialmente ahistóricos. Viven en la burbuja del presente. No saben diferenciar la Guerra de Corea de la Guerra de Vietnam. No saben quién fue aliado de Estados Unidos durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial. Imagínense qué tan diferente sería Estados Unidos si cada estadounidense supiera que esta es la quinta vez que fuerzas occidentales han ido a Afganistán a poner las cosas en orden, y si tuvieran una idea de lo que ha pasado exactamente en esa 4 ocasiones. (Risas) Y eso es lo que pasa, apenas se han ido, y no hay una marca en la arena. O imagínense cómo serían las cosas si la mayoría de los estadounidenses supieran que se nos ha mentido para que participemos en 4 de nuestras 6 guerras. Porque saben, los españoles no hundieron el acorazado Maine el Lusitania no era una embarcación inocente sino que estaba cargada con munición, Vietnam del Norte no atacó a la Séptima Flota. Y, por supuesto, Saddam Hussein odiaba a Al Qaeda y no tenía nada que ver con ellos, y aún así, la administración convenció al 45 % de las personas de que eran compañeros de lucha, cuando se colgaba a uno de la lámpara más cercana. Pero no quiero terminar así de pesimista. El siglo XX nos ha mostrado enormes reservas mentales en gente común de la que ahora hemos reconocido, y la aristocracia estaba convencida de que el ciudadano común no podría lograr nada, que nunca compartirían sus ideas o sus habilidades cognitivas. Lord Curzon dijo una vez que
he saw people bathing in the North Sea, and he said, "Why did no one tell me what white bodies the lower orders have?" As if they were a reptile. Well, Dickens was right and he was wrong. [Correction: Rudyard Kipling] [Kipling] said, "The colonel's lady and Judy O'Grady are sisters underneath the skin." (Applause)
vio personas bañándose en el mar del Norte, y dijo: ¿Por qué nadie me dijo que tan blanca era la plebe?" Como si fueran reptiles. Bueno, Dichens tenía razón y no la tenía. [Kipling] dijo, "La esposa del coronel y Judy O'Grady son hermanas por debajo de la piel". (Aplausos)